Christian **Gosselin** Software Architect | Cloud Dev Lead

github.com/cgos witter.com/cgos in linkedin.com/in/gosselinchristian

📮 +514 779 7273 🛮 @ gosselinchristian@gmail.com 🔻 Montréal, Québec, Canada

• https://cgos.github.io/



I am a pragmatic computer scientist, which over the last twenty years occupied roles such as programmer, software designer, technical leader, architect and more recently cloud engineer. Looking for an opportunity to work in a company where technology, software, security and cloud infrastructure represent their core business

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Application Definition Helm, buildpacks, docker, distroless

> CI/CD Jenkins, CircleCI, Spinnaker, Google Cloud Build

Orchestration Kubernetes, Openshift, GKE, Secret Management (Vault)

Service Proxy Envoy, NGINX

API Gateway Spring Cloud Gateway, Mulesoft, IBM API Connect, Ambassador

Service Mesh Istio

Provisioning Terraform, gcloud

Prometheus, Spring Actuator, Datadog, Stackdriver, Sysdig, FluentD, Splunk, Grafana, Jaeger Monitoring/Logging/Tracing

Programming Language Go, Java, Shell, Groovy

> Other Git, Linux, On-Prem infrastructure, SSL, Microservice Architecture, SOA, Master Data Manage-

ment, ESB, SQL, Incident Response, IAM, Agile, Scrum, Kanban



WORK EXPERIENCE

Present September 2016

Software Architect | Cloud Dev Lead (Consultant), BANQUE NATIONALE DU CANADA, Canada

- > Provided technical leadership/mentorship to successfully deliver the cloud foundation in GCP/Openshift.
- Guided software development teams to follow the industry's best practices in terms of containerization and orchestration with k8s.
- Lead a small team that enabled rest API calls at the bank for the first time through api.bnc.ca. Enforced security guidelines and built CI/CD pipeline.
- Provided the tooling and the process to move from a monthly to a daily production deployment schedule.
- > Established and participated in the implementation of the first Observability stack for microservices application.
- Speaker at the BNC-Tech Conference on System Observability

CNCF CI/CD Observability Kubernetes GKE Openshift GCP Docker Java Spring Boot Maven Circleci Spinnaker | Terraform | Helm | Datadog | Jaeger | Prometheus | Istio | Jenkins | Nexus | JWT | OAuth2 | API Gateway Istio

September 2016 August 2015

Software Architect | Tech Lead | Developer (Consultant), VIDÉOTRON, Canada

- ▶ Lead a team ranging from 6 to 10 persons to organize, design and build an API integration plateform with Mulesoft product.
 - Architecture: Organized the governance around building and deploying APIs.
 - Software design: Created a blueprint design based on a feature required by the business.

Mulesoft API Gateway JWT OAuth2 Docker Swagger RAML Java Sparx EA

June 2015 April 2015

Java Software Developer (Consultant), AIMIA, Canada

Java Spring Maven Oracle

March 2015 October 2011

Software Architect | Java Software Developer (Consultant), BANQUE NATIONALE DU CANADA, Canada

- ▶ Lead teams ranging up to 20 persons over a 6 months period to deliver the SOA and BI master data management solution to the business.
- Technically accountable for the architecture, the development, the integration with SAP, the testing with 3rd parties, deployment in production and post-implementation support.
- > Owned the functional and technical integrity of the solution being implemented. The role of technical integrator is the continuity of the solution architect role during Build, Test and deploy phase of the project.
- Built the architecture, designed software component and coded a complete SOA layer (Java, JAX-WS, Websphere AS, Datapower, WSDL, PL/SQL) responsible for mortgage and insurance related calculations, investments, rates.

Java Spring Maven Oracle SOA Websphere IBM MQ Datapower SAP AIX

March 2015

Sole Owner, ENDPOINT SOLUTIONS INC., Canada

March 2002

- > Started a software development consulting and staffing firm which have grow up to 15 consultants working for various clients.
- ▶ Helped customers to identify their needs and recommended planning and staffing.

Sales Professional Consulting Services Request For Proposals Work Orders

October 2011 April 2007

Tech Lead | Java Software Developer (Consultant), Cogeco, Canada

> Acted as Technical leader on multiple software projects to build and enhance their internet and telephony provisioning systems

Java Spring Maven SQL Oracle Tomcat JAXB JAX-RS JUnit Salesforce OSS Provisioning Linux HP-UX

April 2005 April 2007

Java Software Developer (Consultant), IBM, Canada

- ➤ Lead the software integration between major American and Indian customers. Often requiring night and weekend availability.
- ▶ Built and developed most API and core features for the RPM product.

Java Tomcat Maven DB2 Cruise Control SOAP REST Linux AIX

May 2005 | Java Software Developer (Consultant), HYDRO-QUÉBEC, Canada April 2004 | Java Ant XML SQL Oracle |

April 2004 | Java and C++ Software Developer, CGI, Canada

July 2002 | Java J2EE XML Ant SOAP Struts XML-RPC UML Unix

June 2002 | C and C++ Software Developer, NORTEL, Canada

September 1999 | C++ C CORBA Java Solaris HP-UX Unix

2000 | Java and C++ Software Developer (Fellowship), ERICSSON, Canada 1998 | C++ Java | IETF SIP | CORBA | Solaris |

CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

January 2020 Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer - credential

June 2019 Linux Foundation : Certified Kubernetes Application Developer - credential

April 2016 Mulesoft: Certified MCD Integration and API Associate (credential: 6fa6b599-b51f-32a7-a91d-72a085013fc7)

May 2015 Coursera: The Data Scientist's Toolbox (credential: QYX9F3FJF7)

May 2015 Coursera: The R Programming Language (credential: AKKQ8ULQ2P)

EDUCATION

2001 Master in computer science from Université du Québec à Montréal (Distributed IP IETF Telephony signaling using CORBA)

1998 Baccalauréat in computer science from Université du Québec à Montréal

A LANGUAGES

HIGHLIGHTS

- ➤ Avid Reader (books, articles, blogs).
- > Deep and wide technical interests.
- > Good sense of humor.
- > Self directed and fully accountable.